https://www.luc.edu/its/aboutits/itspoliciesguidelines/privacypolicy/

ITS Rewards & Recognition
TeamsSupportDMSITRSServicesHow to Keep Working - Technology Continuity
Privacy Policy
Scope:
This policy covers all persons accessing Loyola computing resources.
Policy:
This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) is applicable to the information made available, the information collected, and the services offered by Loyola University of Chicago (“Loyola”) directly  through the pages comprising Loyola’s official website (the “Website”) (https://www.luc.edu).  By using Loyola’s Website, you agree to this Privacy Policy.
Loyola’s Website includes links to websites of unaffiliated, private third parties.   Loyola is not responsible for the content, data collection, or data protection practices of such third party websites.  Loyola’s Privacy Policy does not apply to such third party websites and users access such websites at their own risk.
Loyola is dedicated to promoting privacy awareness and compliance.   This Privacy Policy explains what personal data the Website collects, how it is used, shared, and protected, and how you can obtain further information concerning privacy at Loyola.  Loyola will periodically update this Privacy Policy to address new laws, technologies, and information security practices.
What Personal Data Does Loyola’s Website Collect
In order to protect your privacy, Loyola follows the following principles in operating the Website.  The Website does not:
collect more personal data than is necessary;
use your personal data for purposes other than those specified;
keep your personal data if it is no longer needed; or
share your personal data with unaffiliated third parties for marketing purposes.
Except for (1) internet protocol (IP) addresses, (2) certain non-personal information (e.g., the date and time of your visit, the pages you viewed, the region or general location where your computer or device is accessing the Website, the web browser and system used to access the Website, any search terms used and a history of the pages you view), and (3) the use of “cookies,” as described below, the Website does not collect your personal data if you simply visit Loyola’s Website.  It only collects your personal data when you voluntarily provide it, such as by completing a form, requesting information, placing an order, making a payment, or otherwise transacting business with Loyola.  Depending on the subject matter of your transaction, the Website may collect such information as your name, address, phone number, email address, banking information, and preferred method of communicating.  The Website may collect more extensive personal if you are seeking specific services from Loyola, such as registering for classes.
Loyola’s Use of Cookies
Loyola’s Website uses a standard technology called cookies. A cookie is a small text file that Loyola stores on your computer or mobile device when you visit the Website. Cookies facilitate your use of the Website and permit Loyola to perform system analytics that help Loyola to improve the site so that it works more effectively.   Cookies that perform such tasks, such as determining the number of visitors who looked at a specific web page during a given time period, are known as performance cookies.  Portions of Loyola’s Website may use Google Analytics, which also employs cookies to analyze how users use the site for the analysis of site usage and to enhance the user experience.
While Loyola’s Website uses performance cookies, it does not use marketing cookies, which collect your personal information for profiling purposes and the subsequent sending of targeted advertising and content from a third party for unrelated purposes.  You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser.  If you do so, you may be unable to use the full functionality of the Website.
Purposes for Which Loyola Collects Personal Data
Loyola’s Website collects personal data in connection with certain operational purposes. These purposes include, for example: student admissions; class registration; staff and faculty job applications; student housing agreements; and communicating with Website users.
Loyola Efforts to Safeguard Personal Data
Loyola actively works to protect personal data from unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction through appropriate technical measures.   Loyola has put in place a number of policies intended to structurally reduce the risk of data breaches and unauthorized disclosures of personal data, including the following:
Data Classification Policy
Loyola Protected and Loyola Sensitive Data Identification Policy
Electronic Security of Loyola Protected & Loyola Sensitive Data Policy
Physical Security of Loyola Protected and Loyola Sensitive Data Policy
Disposal of Loyola Protected and Loyola Sensitive Data Policy
Encryption Policy
Personal Information Protection Compliance Review Protocol
Data Breach Response Policy
Secure Deletion Procedure
To learn more about these policies, please go to the Information Technology Services Policies and Guidelines Page, https://www.luc.edu/its/aboutits/itspoliciesguidelines/index.shtml.
Children's Privacy
Although Loyola’s Website is not directed at children under the age of 13, Loyola seeks to fully comply with COPPA.  While Loyola cannot always determine with certainty the age of a Website user, the Website does not request, seek or intentionally collect personal information from children under the age of 13.  If Loyola acquires actual knowledge that it has received such information, it will delete it. If in the future Loyola should seek to collect information from children under the age of 13, it will comply with COPPA’s parental “direct notice” and consent requirements in advance of collecting such information.   A parent concerned over a child’s possible use of Loyola’s Website can contact Loyola’s webmaster at webmaster@luc.edu.
Additional GDPR Privacy Notice for EU Residents
If you are accessing Loyola’s Website and are a person located in the European Union (“EU”), a European Economic Area member state, or Switzerland, please see Loyola’s separate privacy notice pursuant to (EU) 2016/679, the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which is available at https://www.luc.edu/gdpr/.
Contacting Loyola Regarding Privacy Policy Questions and Concerns
If you have any questions about Loyola’s Privacy Policy, please contact:
University Marketing & Communications
Loyola University Chicago
820 N. Michigan Ave.
Chicago, IL 60611
Phone: (773) 274-3000
UMC@luc.edu
History:
August 30, 2018: Initial Policy
Last Modified:   Fri, September 25, 2020 4:12 PM CDT
Ethicsline
File a Report
You may file a report about misconduct and ethics or policy violations online or by dialing 855.603.6988
1032 W. Sheridan Ave.,
Chicago,
